Register of the Ivy and Tatiana Litvinov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Tatiana Litvinov File [part II], 1890-2008 (Boxes 20-54)
  - Correspondence, 1933-2008
    - Eikhenbaum, O. B., 1960 (Box-folder 22: 11)
    - Etkind, Efim, 1985 (Box-folder 22: 12)
    - Fediaevskaia, Vera, 1976-1994 (Box-folder 22: 13)
      Includes letters from Konstantin Iasinovskii.
    - Fedorov, Georgii, 1979 (Box-folder 22: 14)
    - Fischer, George, 1974-1987 (Box-folder 22: 15-16)
    - Foyle, John, 2007 (Box-folder 22: 17)
    - Freidin, Gregory, 2003 (Box-folder 22: 18)
      Includes photographs of Freidin family.
    - Gershtein, Emma G., 1976-1995
      Includes photographs and printed matter.
      - 1976-1977 (Box-folder 22: 19)
      - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 22: 20)
      - 1981-1982 (Box-folder 22: 21)
      - 1984-1988 (Box-folder 22: 22)
      - 1990-1991 (Box-folder 23: 1)
      - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 23: 2)
      - 1994-1995 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - Glinka, I., 1989 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - Glotser, Vladimir, 1989 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - Grace, E., 1986 (Box-folder 23: 6)
    - Grigorenko, Petr and Zinaida, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 23: 7)
      Includes photographs.
    - Holroyd-Doveton, J. O., 2002 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - Kovalev, Sergei, circa 1985 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - Kryzhanovskii, Oleg, 1979-1997 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1933-1976
      - Undated (Box-folder 23: 11-12)
      - 1933-1936 (Box-folder 23: 13-14)
      - 1937-1939 (Box-folder 23: 15)
      - 1941 (Box-folder 23: 16)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 23: 17)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 23: 18)
      - 1947-1948 (Box-folder 23: 19)
      - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 23: 20)
      - 1956-1957 (Box-folder 23: 21)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 23: 22)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 23: 23-24, 24: 1-9)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 24: 10-11)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 24: 12)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 24: 13)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 24: 14-15)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 24: 16)
      - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 24: 17)
      - 1972 (Box-folder 25: 1)
      - 1973 (Box-folder 25: 2-3)
      - 1974 (Box-folder 25: 4)
      - 1975 (Box-folder 25: 5-6)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 25: 7)
    - Litvinov, Maksim Maksimovich, 1941-1951
      - 1941 (Box-folder 25: 8)
      - 1942 (Box-folder 25: 9)
      - 1943 (Box-folder 25: 10)
      - 1948-1951 (Box-folder 25: 11)
        Includes letters to Maria Slonim.
    - Litvinov, Mikhail Maksimovich, 1976-1998
      - 1976-1981 (Box-folder 25: 12)
      - 1982-1988 (Box-folder 25: 13)
      - 1993-1998 (Box-folder 25: 14)
    - Litvinov, Pavel, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 25: 15)
    - Litvinova, Nina, 1976-2000
      - 1976-1980 (Box-folder 25: 16)
      - 1981-1985 (Box-folder 25: 17)
      - 1986-1989 (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - 1990-1991 (Box-folder 26: 2)
      - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 26: 3)
      - 1994-2000 (Box-folder 26: 4)
    - Litvinova (nee Iasinovskaia), Flora, 1973-2001
      - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 26: 5)
      - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 26: 6)
      - 1977 (Box-folder 26: 7)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 26: 8)
      - 1979 (Box-folder 26: 9)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 26: 10)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 26: 11)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 26: 12)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 27: 1)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 27: 2)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 27: 3-4)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 27: 5-6)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 27: 7)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 27: 8)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 27: 9)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 27: 10)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 27: 11)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 28: 1)
      - 1993 (Box-folder 28: 2)
      - 1994 (Box-folder 28: 3)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 28: 4)
      - 1996-1998 (Box-folder 28: 5-6)
      - 1999-2001 (Box-folder 28: 7)
    - Lozovskaia, Klara I., 1955-1976 (Box-folder 28: 8)
    - Maxwell, Emilia, 1988 (Box-folder 28: 9)
    - Maxwell, William, 1967-1998
      - 1967-1971 (Box-folder 28: 10)
      - 1976-1983 (Box-folder 28: 11)
      - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 28: 12)
      - 1986-1990 (Box-folder 28: 13)
      - 1993-1998 (Box-folder 28: 14)
    - Naiman, Anatolii, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 28: 15)
    - Nekrasov, Viktor, 1983-1987
      - 1983 (Box-folder 29: 1)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 29: 2)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 29: 3)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 29: 4)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 29: 5)
    - Norman, Dorothy, 1983 (Box-folder 29: 6)
    - Phillimore, Robert Godfrey, circa 1985 (Box-folder 29: 7)
      Includes writings by Phillimore.
    - Pozina, Basia G., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 29: 8-9)
    - Rantz, Berta, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 29: 10)
    - Reshetovskaia (Reshetovskaya), Natal'ia (Natalya), 1982 (Box-folder 29: 11)
    - Rounton Design, 1982 (Box-folder 29: 12)
    - Simson, Kathleen von (International P.E.N.), 1978-1983 (Box-folder 29: 13-14)
      Includes Gabriel Superfin letters to Simson and Tatiana Litvinov.
    - Slonim, Il'ia L'vovich, 1941-1973
      Includes letters to Ivy Litvinov.
      - 1941 (Box-folder 29: 15-17)
      - 1942-1944 (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - 1945-1947 (Box-folder 30: 2)
      - 1949-1951 (Box-folder 30: 3)
        Includes letters from Maksim Litvinov.
      - 1954-1955 (Box-folder 30: 4)
      - 1957-1959 (Box-folder 30: 5)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 30: 6)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 30: 7)
      - 1962 (Box-folder 30: 8)
      - 1963 (Box-folder 30: 9)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 30: 10)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 30: 11)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 30: 12)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 30: 13)
        Includes a letter from Kornei Chukovskii.
      - 1968 (Box-folder 30: 14)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 30: 15)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 30: 16)
      - 1971 (Box-folder 31: 1)
      - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 31: 2)
    - Slonim (Chalidze), Vera, 1955-2008 (Box-folder 31: 3)
    - Slonim (Phillimore), Mariia, 1959-1995
      - 1959-1969 (Box-folder 31: 4)
      - 1970-1974 (Box-folder 31: 5)
      - 1995 (Box-folder 31: 6)
    - Snegirev, Gennadii, 1990 (Box-folder 31: 7)
    - Sollogub, V., 2001 (Box-folder 31: 8)
    - Spear, A., 1979 (Box-folder 31: 9)
    - Spencer, Derek, 1992 (Box-folder 31: 10)
    - Superfin, Gabriel, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 31: 11)
    - Vakidin, Viktor, 1978-1985 (Box-folder 31: 12)
    - Virago Press, 1985-1989
      - 1985 (Box-folder 31: 13)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 31: 14)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 31: 15)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 31: 16)
      - 1989 (Box-folder 31: 17)
    - Zavolzhskaia, A. K., 1982 (Box-folder 31: 18)
    - Zaks, Boris, 1976-1990
      - 1976-1978 (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 32: 2)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 32: 3)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 32: 4)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 32: 5)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - 1986 (Box-folder 32: 7)
      - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 32: 8)
      - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 32: 9)
    - Zinik, Zinovii, 1993 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Diaries, 1951-2007
    - 1951-1952 (Box-folder 32: 11)
    - 1959, 1962-1965, 1967 (Box-folder 32: 12)
    - 1963-1964 (Box-folder 32: 13)
    - 1966 (Box-folder 32: 14)
    - 1967-1970, 1974 (Box-folder 32: 15)
    - 1968-1972 (Box-folder 32: 16)
    - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 33: 1)
    - 1970, 1972, 1974 (Box-folder 33: 2)
    - 1970-1976 (Box-folder 33: 3)
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 33: 4)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 33: 5)
    - 1972-1974 (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 33: 7)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - 1975, 1976, 1997 (Box-folder 34: 2)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 34: 3)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 34: 4)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 34: 5)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 34: 6, 35: 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - 1982, 1985 (Box-folder 35: 3)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 35: 4)
    - 1983-1985 (Box-folder 35: 5)
    - 1983, 1986 (Box-folder 36: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 36: 2)
    - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 36: 3)
    - 1985-1987 (Box-folder 36: 4)
    - 1985, 1988, 1999- 2002 (Box-folder 36: 5)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 36: 6)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 36: 7)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 36: 8)
    - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - 1987, 1989 (Box-folder 37: 2)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 37: 3-4)
    - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 37: 5)
    - 1989, 1992 (Box-folder 37: 6)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 38: 1-2)
    - 1991-1998 (Box-folder 38: 3)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 39: 1-2)
    - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 39: 3)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 39: 4)
    - 1997, 2000, 2007 (Box-folder 39: 5)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - 1998, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - 2001-2003 (Box-folder 40: 3)
    - 2001, 2004, 2006 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - 2002-2003 (Box-folder 40: 5-6)
    - 2004 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - 2005-2006 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - 2007 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - Notebooks, 1965-1986
    - 1965 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - 1973 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 41: 5)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Address books, 1989, 2006 (Box-folder 41: 8-9)
  - Art works and exhibits, 1967-2005
    - Charcoal and graphite pencil sketches, 1970-2000 (Boxes 42-44)
    - Exhibits, 1967-2005 (Box-folder 45: 1-7)
      Includes exhibition catalogues, correspondence, visitors' comments, and clippings.
  - Photographs, 1890-2002
    Includes photographs depicting Tatiana Litvinov's family and friends through the years, arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Chukovskaii family, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 45: 8)
    - Herbert, Sandy, 1917 (Box-folder 45: 9)
    - Kopelev, Lev, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 45: 10)
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1890-1977
      - 1890-1920 (Box-folder 45: 11)
      - 1928-1946 (Box-folder 45: 12)
      - 1950-1970 (Box-folder 45: 13)
      - 1973-1977 (Box-folder 45: 14)
    - Litvinov, Maksim Maksimovich and Anatolii Vasil'evich Lunacharskii, 1930 (Box-folder 45: 15)
    - Litvinov, Mikhail, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - Litvinov, Pavel, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 46: 2)
    - Litvinov, Tatiana, 1928-2002
      - 1928-1954 (Box-folder 46: 3)
      - 1970-1973 (Box-folder 46: 4)
      - 1982-1983 (Box-folder 46: 5)
      - 1986-1988 (Box-folder 46: 6)
      - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 46: 7)
      - 1992-1996 (Box-folder 46: 8-9)
      - 1997-1999 (Box-folder 46: 10-11)
      - 2000-2002 (Box-folder 45: 12)
    - Naiman, Anatolii, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 13)
    - Nekrasov, Viktor, 1983 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Slonim (Phillimore), Mariia, 1975-1995 (Box-folder 46: 15)
  - Speeches and writings, 1959-1995
    - Background material, 1959-1995 (Boxes 46-48)
      Includes notes, related fragments, and typescripts (incomplete).
    - "Detstvo na Sofiiskoi naberezhnoi," typescript, circa 1980 (Box-folder 49: 1-6)
      Includes drafts.
    - "Family Matters," typescript, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 49: 7)
      Includes drafts, notes, and correspondence.
    - The Geometry of Love, by John Cheever, translated into Russian by Tatiana Litvinov, 1966-1986 (Box-folder 49: 8-9)
      Includes typescript, clippings, and correspondence.
    - "Iunost' na Spiridonovke (Youth on Spiridonovka),", circa 1937 (Box-folder 50: 1-7)
    - Joseph Brodsky: notes for the memorial evening at London University, 1995 (Box-folder 50: 8)
    - "Moi Stikhi," poems, holograph manuscript and typescript, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 50: 9)
    - "Opaly i voina,", circa 1988 (Box-folder 50: 10-11)
      Includes draft, notes, and clippings.
    - Oral history interview of Tatiana Litvinov by Valerii Chalidze, transcript, 1981 (Box-folder 51: 1-9)
    - "Otrochestvo (Otrochestvo u Krasnykh vorot)," typescripts, circa 1970 (Box-folder 51: 10-14)
  - Writings by others, 1957-1989
    - Chukovskii, Evgenii, "Detektivnaia istoriia," Teleks, New York, 1989 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - Chukovskii, Kornei Ivanovich, "Onegin na chuzhbine," typescript, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 52: 2-6)
      Includes drafts, notes, correspondence, and Tatiana Litvinov's remarks.
    - Danielson, Elena S., "The Elusive Litvinov Memoirs," Slavic Review, 1989 Fall (Box-folder 52: 7)
    - Pease, Monica Dionis Hudleston, "An Informal Autobiography," typescript, circa 1977 (Box-folder 52: 8)
    - Sheinis, Z. S., "Moemy dal'neishemy potomstvu," Iunost', No. 7, 1966 (Box-folder 52: 9)
    - Vinokurov, Evgenii, "Kharaktery," Sovetskii Pisatel', Moscow, 1965 (Box-folder 52: 10)
  - Clippings, 1925-2004
    Includes photocopies of printed matter.
    - General, 1960-1975 (Box-folder 52: 11)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, 1991-2004 (Box-folder 52: 12)
    - Carswell, John, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Chalidze, Valerii, 1972 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Chukovskii, Kornei Ivanovich, 1982 -1990 (Box-folder 53: 3-4)
    - Litvinov, Ivy, 1960-1990 (Box-folder 53: 5-6)
    - Litvinov, Maksim Maksimovich, 1925-1991 (Box-folder 53: 7-9)
    - Litvinov, Pavel, 1967-1992 (Box-folder 53: 10)
    - Litvinov family, 1960-1992 (Box-folder 53: 11)
    - Sakharov, Andrei Dmitrievich, 1989 (Box-folder 53: 12)
    - Soviet dissidents, 1982 (Box-folder 53: 13)
  - Sound recording, Tatiana Maksimovna Litvinov's oral history interview, Imperial War Museum, London, 1991 (Box 55)
    Includes two compact sound cassettes.
  - Oversize materials, 1928-1950
    - Clippings regarding Maksim Maksimovich Litvinov, 1928-1936 (Box-folder 54: 1-3)
    - Il'ia L'vovich Slonim drawings, circa 1950 (Box-folder 54: 4)